<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="methods">
        A method is a collection of statements that perform some specific task and return result to the caller.
        A method can perform some specific task without returning anything.
        Methods allow us to reuse the code without retyping the code.
        In Java, every method must be part of some class which is different from languages like C, C++ and Python.
Methods are time savers and help us to reuse the code without retyping the code.
    </string>

    <string name="methoddeclarartiona">
        Method declaration has six components:
    </string>
    <string name="modifiersa">
        Modifier-: Defines access type of the method i.e. from where it can be accessed in your application.
        In Java, there 4 type of the access specifiers.
    </string>
    <string name="modifiersb">
        public: accessible in all class in your application.
    </string>
    <string name="modifiersc">
        protected: accessible within the class in which it is defined and in its subclass(es)
    </string>
    <string name="modifiersd">
        private: accessible only within the class in which it is defined.
    </string>
    <string name="modifierse">
        default (declared/defined without using any modifier) :
        accessible within same class and package within which its class is defined.
    </string>

    <string name="returntype">
        The return type : The data type of the value returned by the the method or void if does not return a value.
    </string>
    <string name="methodname">
        Method Name : the rules for field names apply to method names as well, but the convention is a little different
    </string>
    <string name="parameterlist">
        Parameter list : Comma separated list of the input parameters are defined,
        preceded with their data type, within the enclosed parenthesis.
        If there are no parameters, you must use empty parentheses ().
    </string>
    <string name="exceptionlist">
        Exception list : The exceptions you expect by the method can throw, you can specify these exception(s).
    </string>
    <string name="methodbody">
        Method body : it is enclosed between braces. The code you need to be executed to perform your intended operations.
    </string>
    <string name="methodsignature">
        Method signature: It consists of method name and parameter list (number of parameters,
        type of the parameters and order of the parameters).
        Return type and exceptions are not considered as part of it.
    </string>
    <string name="namingmethods">
         A method name is typically a single word that should be a verb in lowercase or multi-word,
        that begins with a verb in lowercase followed by adjective, noun…..
        After the first word, first letter of each word should be capitalized. For example, findSum,
computeMax, setX and getX

Generally, A method has a unique name within the class in whichit is defined but sometime
        a method might have same name as other method name within the same class as method overloading is allowed in Java.
    </string>
    <string name="classes">
        A class is a user defined blueprint or prototype from which objects are created.
        It represents the set of properties or methods that are common to all objects of one type.
        In general, class declarations can include these components, in order:
    </string>
</resources>